<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project on Kramer Ecology Lab</title>
    <link>https://kramera3.github.io/tags/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Project on Kramer Ecology Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Andrew M Kramer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kramera3.github.io/tags/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Allee effects</title>
      <link>https://kramera3.github.io/project/allee-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kramera3.github.io/project/allee-effects/</guid>
      <description>Low density populations can be subject to Allee effects, also known as positive density dependence, which result in reduced population growth rate and increased risk of extinction in small populations. These dynamics are crucial to the success of invasive species, management of harvested populations and conservation of threatened and endangered species. My research focuses on understanding the mechanisms and consequences of positive density dependence, which is important in aquatic species from sea urchins to salmon to copepods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invasive species ecology</title>
      <link>https://kramera3.github.io/project/invasive-species/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kramera3.github.io/project/invasive-species/</guid>
      <description>A current focus of my research is forecasting the potential distributions of invasive species, including dreissenid mussels and lionfish. I am using a combination of parametric and non-parametric models, including application of novel machine learning approaches. In addition to commonly considered climatic predictors I am working on applications of deep learning that use time series of climate data directly. I am also currently working with the Invacost project to better understand the economic costs of non-native species.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macroscale spread of disease</title>
      <link>https://kramera3.github.io/project/disease-spread/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kramera3.github.io/project/disease-spread/</guid>
      <description>Part of my computational research examines methods for modeling spread on networks. This work applies to several pathogens, including white-nose syndrome in bats, Ebola in central and west Africa, and SARS-Cov2. By modeling the epidemics on a network, we can better capture the pattern of spread, identify key factors influencing that pattern, and produce effective forecasts. My current work addresses two important problems: simplifying the complex networks that often result from these models and coupling processes at the local scale to macro-scale spread on the network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zooplankton Coexistence</title>
      <link>https://kramera3.github.io/project/zooplankton-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kramera3.github.io/project/zooplankton-communities/</guid>
      <description>There is much room for improving understanding of the contribution of interspecific interactions, such as competition and predation, to extinction risk. I am looking at the interactions of local native and non-native cladocerans, as well as zooplankton community recovery following removal of non-native fish in Sierra Nevada lakes. I am also working to explain why temporary wetlands at the Savannah River Ecology Laboratory are able to support a hyper-diverse zooplankton community.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>